Hello everyone, welcome back to this new
video.  So finally the allotment of ICICI Pidencal AMC is
out which you can
check on the Fintech website of the register of this IPO.
By the way, you must have
checked I Guess by now and hopefully you must have got the
allotment also.  You might have got some shares of
this.  That's why you are
watching this video.  Now, however, allotment was
not very tough in this.  Allotment has been very easy.
But the main thing is
in which category and
for how many allotments you had applied and how many
allotments have been allotted to you.  Because the one thing is that the
share holders quota has its own separate
calculation.  Then there is the retail category
, there is small HI, there is big HI.  So
people have applied it with many combinations.
By the way,
what was your status?  What is your allotment status
in this IPO?  Or
please tell us in the comment box below how many lots you had
applied for and how many shares
you have got in them.  Now see, the allotment
process has been completed in this.  Now only one
last step is left and that is the listing of this company.
After that, ICIC PEL shares will
start trading normally on NSE and BS
and its listing is going to happen just one day
later i.e. on 19th December.
So, whoever has been allotted this IPO,
now they have to decide what should be
their strategy on the day of listing
?  Should I sell these shares
or this company
can perform very well in the future and I should
hold these shares for the long term.
So see, in today's video we
will definitely discuss this thing but before that let
me tell you a little about its GMP,
about the grey market premium.  So see, for the last two days its
GMP has been continuously around 15%
and now it is quite stable.  Even now,
shares of ICIC PDL are
trading at a premium of exactly ₹350 in the grey market.
While I am recording this video.  And
if I tell you in percentage terms, then
it is a GMP of 16% and now since
only one day is left for its listing,
hopefully
we will not see much volatility from here onwards and the
GMP will probably remain in this range now.  Well,
if we calculate on the basis of 15%,
let's assume that it is going to be listed at 15%,
then the listing price of ICICI Pencil AMC can be
around ₹2500.  Yes, this company can be listed at the ₹2500 mark.
And if this
happens then in this IP we can get a
profit of around ₹2000 on one lot.  And
if you have got HA allotment then your
profit amount can be around ₹30 to
₹32,000.  However, this is just an
assumption based on its GMP.  The rest is
that you should not consider its GMP as something set in stone.
This has happened
many times in the past that the GMP is somewhere else
and the listing price is showing something else.
So its actual listing may be
much higher or much lower than this.
So you have to keep this thing in mind.
By the way, whatever updates there will be regarding its GMP
before listing, you will get them from time to time
on my Telegram channel.  So if
you want, you can join this Telegram channel.
Its link is
given in the description box below.  And
yes, let me give you one more update that on the
day of its listing, when it will be listed between 9:00 am to 10:00 am,
I will also be live on my channel in
which we will track its pre-open time
and discuss everything else also.
So if you have also got allotment in this
and you also want to join that live, then
you must subscribe to this channel right now on
19th
between 9:00 to 10 in the morning.  Now let's talk
about its listing day strategy.  So
look, here we are going to discuss both the scenarios.
If you sell the shares or
you hold them, then I will
also tell you whether I am going to sell the shares that I have
received or I
plan to hold them.  So first
if we talk about holding, if you are
thinking of long term holding then what are those
points which can work in your favor.
So see, the first
point is that this is a company of ICIC Group.  It
is the second biggest MC company
in India.  Very active in the mutual fund space.
Highest number of schemes
if any company has
in India Mutual Fund.  So it is with ICICI Pencal AMC
only.  So its business seems very future
proof.  As the capital market continues to
grow in India, it is bound to
grow eventually.  The
more active people are in the stock market and the
more they participate in the stock market, the more
direct benefit these companies and
capital market companies will get.  So
its business seems to be a very solid business
and its business is also future proof.  There will never be a
shortage of opportunities here.
So first thing is the business of this company.  The
second point is the
growth of the financial numbers of this company.  See, the company
already operates on a very large base.
Their annual revenue is
around ₹5000 crore.  But
even after that, the growth of the company's revenue and profit amount
is in the range of 25 to 30%, which is
a very amazing growth.  So they are convinced that
even on such a large base the company is growing at such a good
speed.  So this
is a very good point.  And one more thing is that
since this is a very big sized company,
their business will almost always remain stable.  Whether there is
stability in the stock price
or not, you will
not see much ups and downs in its business.
And anyway ICICI Group
is its promoter.  So one thing is that it is a
professionally managed company.  So there will be
no corporate governance issues in this company.  So these are all the points
which can work in your favor if you hold this company or rather its
CS for the long term.
Can work in your support.  Now let's talk
about booking listing guesses.
So, its biggest support
point will be its overvaluation.  You must have already
heard a lot that this
company
is highly overvalued according to its IPO price.  Compared to its peer group
companies like HDFC AMC or Ni Napon
or UTI AMC, it
is trading at a premium of more than two times and if it gets listed at a premium of 10-12% then the
valuation will be stretched even further.  So,
we are not getting this company at a very comfortable valuation, neither
according to the IP price nor
after listing.  So overvaluation
is one of the biggest triggers that we should think about selling these stocks.  The
second
point is the cyclical nature of business.  See, all the
companies in the capital market are
a bit cyclical.  Whenever the stock
market performs well, the
business of these companies also grows and their
stock price also starts increasing very well.
But whenever the market
remains sideways or there is a slight downtrend in the market, the
business of these companies also deteriorates and the stock
price also performs accordingly.  As
you can see at present, the market is
not that good.  So, the condition of all the capital
market stocks, especially CDSL,
Anjal One or all the stock broking
companies which are depository companies, is
also not that good.  He has been
sideways for quite some time.  So this risk will
always remain in this company also.  Also,
look if you are the type of investor
who prefers change to growth.  If you invest only in mid cap
and small cap, then
this company may not fit in your portfolio.
This is already a fairly large sized
company.  Its market capitalization
according to IP price is more than ₹1 lakh crore.
So, here it is possible that
we may not get that growth flavour in the long run.
Because this company has already penetrated all over India.
So,
we may not see that much growth in the future.
And the current growth rate
may also slow down a bit.
So these are all the points which
indicate to you or give you some
support that you
can also think about selling your shares.  Now,
however, I am not giving you any recommendation whether
you should sell your shares
or hold them.  But now let me
tell you what I am going to do.
So see, I have
discussed this in many videos that I
generally apply in IPO only for the purpose of listing gains.
And mostly I
book listing gains only.  And this is going to be
my same plan in this IPO also.
If there were not such easy allotments
in this IPO and there was no GMP of 10, 12, 15%,
then perhaps I would not have even applied in this IPO
due to its overvaluation.  But when
the market is ready to pay a premium for it, then
why should we lag behind?  So if
it gets listed at a premium of around 8, 10, 12%, then
brother, I am going to
think about selling my shares.
And that too probably in pre-open time only.
And by the way, if you also want to do the same, that is,
sell your shares in the pre-open time, then on the
day of its listing,
I will provide you the links of its pre-open time
on my Telegram channel.
From where you can track its pre-open time
and place your selling order.
According to its opening price.  So you must join my Telegram channel.
Its link is
given below in the description box and pin comment.
So for now, my
plan is to sell these shares.  If I get even 8-10%
listing gains, then since I had
applied for the purpose of listing gains only,
I will sell my shares.  However,
we will have to take some quick decisions according to its listing price.
Which is one that
I cannot tell you in advance right now.
When it is listed,
depending on the situation,
we may have to take some new decisions at the moment.   Had to
change my decisions.  And by the way, I will be
live at the time of listing
and I will hopefully sell my shares live.
So if you want, you can join live.
For that you have to subscribe to this channel.
By the way,
what does your gut feeling say about its listing
?  Please let us know in the comment box below whether ICIC PE AMC will be
listed at a premium of more than 15% or not.
Otherwise, if you have not liked this video yet, then
like the video and
also subscribe to the channel.  And yes,
how to sell IPO shares during pre-open time.
If you want to see this entire
process live then you
can watch this video of mine.  [music]